# **BRITNEY EPPS**

Detroit, MI 48227 704-779-5884 britneygill0215@gmail.com

### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Expert Staff Software engineering professional with proven skills and progressive experience. Accomplished in coordinating teams, resources and projects to meet short-term objectives and realize long-term vision. Manages projects and designs effectively according to established roadmaps and adapting to dynamic challenges and roadblocks.

## **SKILLS**

- Data Structure Proficiency
- Software Architecture Design
- $\bullet \ \hbox{Continuous Integration and} \\$

- Web Application Development
- Project Management Experience
- Database Management

Deployment

Design and development

#### **EXPERIENCE**

Director of Engineering

December 2022 - Current

JustAir | Detroit, MI

- Spearheaded the strategic direction and operational processes of the engineering department at JustAir, enhancing team productivity and project delivery.
- Led the backend development of JustAir's main tech stack, ensuring robust and scalable software solutions.
- Directed cross-functional teams in the deployment of advanced technology solutions, significantly improving air quality monitoring services.

**Engineering Manager** 

January 2022 - July 2022

Code for America | San Francisco, CA

- Managed 6 direct reports of different level of expertise (apprentice to staff engineer)
- Helped hire software engineers, engineering managers, product managers, and Director of Engineering ops to fill positions of need in the department
- Handle restructuring of teams to best fit the requirements of now

Senior Software Engineer

April 2020 - January 2022

Code for America | San Francisco, CA

- Utilized Java, Spring and Thymeleaf as a fullstack developer for the SHIBA (State hosted integrated benefits application) team working on delivering a web application for the state of Minnesota and its citizens to apply for safety net programs at the state level.
- Led active role on team in setting up the alert and monitoring system, Datadog.
- Reduced time for applying to 9 safety net programs from 55 minutes to 12 minutes.
- Created retry systems around the state systems to keep applications being processed, such as resending failures and emailing them if the current SFTP pipeline has errors.

- Engineering mentor for an apprentice out of bootcamp, as well as for the other developers in different levels of their career.
- Refactored a test suite utilizing JUnit and Selenium from 20 min to <4 min.
- Hosted workshops for team mates and other developers to break down technologies such as Sentry, Datadog, and other tools we use to maintain the quality of our code base.
- Assisted in increasing the safety net team numbers, being involved in the interview process for Sr. Product Managers and Engineering Managers. Wrote a blog post on how to use Thymeleaf with SpringBoot
- Built and tested automation tools for infrastructure provisioning.

Software Engineer

November 2018 - April 2020

StockX | Detroit, MI

- Backend developer for the POSSE Team that focused on payments, operations, services, and shipment details dealing with orders on the StockX platform (web and mobile).
- Contributed software engineering expertise to development of products through the agile lifecycle, from requirements definition through successful deployment.
- Worked with a team of software developers to refactor a monolith into multiple microservices
- Designed microservices that utilized REST APIs built in Golang & NodeJS.
- Lead conversations about sofware architecture discussion and software implementation dealing with the release of StockX's All-In Market which directly increased our global market share.
- Utilized AWS terraform in order to create environments that could connect microservices together as well as spin up new services as needed.
- Wrote, reviewed, and tested code for multiple software projects

Software Engineer

January 2012 - October 2018

GE Aviation | Cincinnati, OH

- Backend developer using Java/Spring framework for Repairs Operations Advisor which allows GE Aviation to save \$75 million in cost through the repairs process.
- Maintained and evolved backed infrastructure utilizing Java/Spring framework for Project Advisor application who assisted engine program leads in saving \$50 million in new engine program investments.
- Facilitated STEM related activities for children as the STEM Board Co-Lead for the Womens Network at GE Digitial.
- Collaborated with cross functional teams to develop a suite of tools in the supply chain space for GE Aviation that resulted in a savings of \$150 million across the engine manufacturing and repair process.
- Completed a rigorous rotational leadership program while also acquiring a master in Computer Science from the University of Detroit.
- Designed and implemented a big data solution for a Fortune 500 company, resulting in a 10% reduction in energy usage.

#### **EDUCATION**

Master of Science (M.S.) - Computer Science University of Cincinnati, Cincinnati, OH

May 2015

North Carolina A&T State University, Greensboro, NC